The Show of Shows is a music film directed by John G. Adolfi.
Now hear this.
The studio that gave the cinema its voice offered 1929 audiences a chance to see and hear multiple silent-screen favorites for the first time in
a gaudy, grandiose music-comedy-novelty revue that also included Talkie stars, Broadway luminaries and of course, Rin-Tin-Tin.
Frank Fay hosts a jamboree that, among its 70+ stars, features bicyclers, boxing champ Georges Carpentier, chorines in terpsichore kickery, sister acts, Myrna Loy in two-strip Technicolor as an exotic Far East
beauty, John Barrymore in a Shakespearean soliloquy (adding an on-screen voice to his legendary profile for the first time) and Winnie Lightner famously warbling the joys of Singing in the Bathtub.
Watch, rinse, repeat!
Master of Ceremonies, played by Frank Fay.
Hansom Cabby in "What Became of the Floradora Boys" number" / (segment
"Recitations") / Soldier (segment "Rifle Execution"), played by Lloyd Hamilton.
Street Cleaner in 'What Became of the Floradora Boys'
Number / 'Tramp' Ballet, played by Lupino Lane.
Waiter in 'What Became of the Floradora Boys' Number, played by Ben Turpin.
Performer in 'What Became of the Floradora Boys' & 'Meet My
Sister' Numbers, played by Sally O'Neil.
Performer in 'What Became of the Floradora Boys' & 'Meet
My Sister' Numbers, played by Alice Day.
Show Boat is a 1929 American pre-Code sound part-talkie romantic drama
film based on the 1926 novel Show Boat by Edna Ferber.
The film initially did not use the 1927 stage musical of the same name as a source, but scenes were later
added into the film incorporating two of the songs from the musical as well as other songs.
Many of these songs from the stage show were featured in a special
prologue that was added to the picture before it was released.
This film was produced and released by Universal.
Like the majority of films during the early sound era, a silent version was
made for movie theatres that had not yet converted to sound.
The film was long believed to be lost, but most of it has been found and
released on LaserDisc and shown on Turner Classic Movies.
Like most early sound films the film was released in both
sound-on-disc and sound-on-film versions.
A number of Vitaphone type records for the sound-on-disc
version were located in the mid-1990s.
The soundtrack for the film was originally recorded using the sound-on-film Western Electric process and transferred to
the disc format for those theatres that did not have the capability of playing the sound-on-film format.
Two more soundtrack records were discovered in 2005.
As a film first published in 1929, it entered the
public domain on January 1, 2025.
The film explores themes of guillotine, revue, dog, german shepherd.